Tim Caswell

821 Dublin #105 Richardson, TX 75080 Phone: 972-499-0647

Email: tim@creationix.com Google Talk: tim@creationix.com Portfolio: www.creationix.com

Summary

I have worked many years in different fields, but out of all my work I've enjoyed the most (and been the best at) web programming. I have over 13 years total programming experience. I've done it for school, work, and fun and I know the little things that can cause problems and how to avoid them. I practice best-practices and insist on clean, easy-to-maintain code. My style of coding has been beneficial to many of the companies I've worked for in both maintenance and overall cost to develop. I adhere to strict standards compliance and constantly research the latest and greatest in programming techniques. I'm confident that my unique skills will be a great asset to any programming project.

Technical Skills

Languages and Technologies

- HTML/XHTML (8 years)
- CSS (5 years)
- AJAX (4 years)
- Ruby / Rails (1 year)
- | Javascript (9 years)
- > PHP (6 years)
- Linux (6 years)
- OSX (3 years)
- Apache (6 years)

- MySQL (2 years)
- Postgresgl (2 year)
- Python (3 years)
- GTK/Glade (2 years)
- Basic (12 years)
- > SSH (4 years)
- > Java (1 year)
- > C (1 year)
- > C++ (1 year)

Education

University of Texas at Dallas

Major: Degrees:

Estimated Completion:

Fall 2006 - Current

Software Engineering/Computer Science Bachelor's & Master's of Science

Spring 2010

N/A

Fall 2004

Texarkana College

Major: Degree:

Pre-Engineering

Southern Arkansas University

Major:

Pre-Engineering Degree:

University of Central Arkansas

Major: Degree: Fall 2000-Spring 2001 Computer Science N/A

Fall 2005-Summer 2006

Tim Caswell Confidential 1

Professional Experience

New Media Gateway - Dallas, TX

2007 - Present

Web Developer (effective team lead)

- Assisting other developers with tough problems and how to use the frameworks I develop.
- Design and implement new add-ons to large software-as-a-service application.
- > Train new employees, fix critical issues for customers, develop and maintain the software frameworks that the system is built upon.

Miracom Network, Ltd. - Richardson, TX

2007

Programmer, System Admin

- Work on a team to maintain a large web based application for remote print management.
- > Administer and setup an integration server and several web servers.

Robert Half Technologies - Dallas, TX

2006 - 2007

Consultant / Web Developer

- Made websites for clients in PHP, Mysql
- > Short support calls to fix Unix and Linux systems

Creationix Software Innovations - Richardson, TX

2000 - Present

Freelance Designer / Programmer

- > Worked on small contracts and designed in-house products
- Web Design using PHP, Python, XHTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL, Ruby, and Rails
- Custom board and card games
- > Open Source Development
- Linux systems administration
- Worked as main subcontractor to Phenom-Business-Solutions on several large sites.

Texarkana Gazette - Texarkana. TX

2006

Online Production Technician

- > Supervised the pre-press crew and assist as needed
- Researched and developed new computer technologies for the company.
 (Using Linux and Open source programs)
- > Technical Support for close to 250 workstations.
- Maintained internal websites and servers

Insty-Prints - Texarkana, TX

2005 - 2006

Graphic Designer / Web Design Specialist

- > Web design and maintenance for company and customers
- > Typesetting, graphic design, logo design and printing
- Customer Service, Research and Design, Marketing

EPES – Magnolia, AR

2004

Programmer / Designer

- Designed and proposed in-house software
 - Developed and programmed software in Java and Python
 - > Tested software and trained employees on how to use software.

Tim Caswell 2 Confidential